（少女）ハア ハア…
（少女）きゃあ！
Mommy! What about the bomb shelter?
お母さん！　防空壕(ぼうくうごう)は？
Mommy!
お母さん！
Tokyo: Present Day
（三上(みかみ)）平和だなあ
Sure is peaceful...
I live a totally normal, uneventful life.
（三上）
なんということもない普通の人生
I graduated from college, got a job
at a major general contracting firm,
大学を出て
一応 大手といわれる
ゼネコンに入社し
worked my way up the ladder,
and started making decent money.
それなりに出世し
そこそこの給料をもらい
I'm a perfectly content 37-year-old man.
何不自由ない37歳
何か足りないとすれば
If there's anything missing in my
life right now, it's a girlfriend.
今 彼女がいない
ということか
In fact, I haven't had a
girlfriend in all my 37 years...
というか
彼女いない歴 37年
But not having one doesn't
bother me at all, really.
まあ 別に いなくて困る
というものでもないし…
Senpai!
（田村(たむら)）先輩！
（田村）先輩 こっちです
Over here, Senpai!
（三上）田村　悪い 少し遅れた
Tamura, sorry I'm a bit late.
で… 相談って？
So, what'd you want to discuss?
（沢渡）
はじめまして 沢渡美穂(さわたりみほ)です
Hello! I'm Sawatari Miho.
いつも お見かけしますが
お話しするのは初めてですね
I see you around a lot, but this
is our first time speaking.
あ… ども　三上 悟(さとる)です
Oh... Hi. I'm Mikami Satoru.
I know who you are, of course. You're famous.
沢渡さんは有名だから
知ってますよ
What?! Famous?!
えっ！　有名って？
Yeah, I mean, all those rumors...
まあ いろいろ うわさがね
Wh-What rumors?!
な… 何のうわさですか？
Easy, Miho. He's just teasing you.
美穂
からかわれてるだけだって
先輩も
それくらいにしてくださいよ
Go easy on her, Senpai.
すまんな
Sorry about that.
（三上）
ていうか 何だ？
結婚の相談か何かか？
What is this, anyway?
Is he looking for marriage advice?
（田村）
ここじゃ なんですから
No need to stand around.
Let's talk while we eat.
メシ食いながら
話しましょう
You like yakiniku, don't you, Senpai?
先輩
焼き肉 好きでしたよね
I booked a great place for us.
いい店 予約してありますから
Jeez, he arranged one of
my favorites for dinner?
（三上）
ったく 俺の好きなものを
用意してあるとか…
Kid sure knows how to treat his senpai.
よくできた後輩だ
すぐ近くです
It's just up ahead.
（三上）
しょうがない
素直に祝福してやるか
Well, I guess I should offer
them my congratulations.
（通行人）え？　なになに？
（通り魔）ハア ハア…
田村！
Tamura!
S-Senpai!
せ… 先輩！
（三上）
な… 何だ これ？
Wh-What is this?
熱すぎる
It's too hot...
勘弁して… ほしい
I don't... want this...
Confirmed.
（大賢者(だいけんじゃ)）
確認しました
Heat Resistance acquisition successful.
“対熱耐性”獲得
成功しました
How the hell could I get stabbed and die?!
（三上）
刺されて死ぬとか… ないわ
It hurts
Confirmed.
（大賢者）
確認しました
Get Stabbed and Die
“刺突耐性”獲得
成功しました
Stab Resistance acquisition successful.
Stab Resistance
Continuing...
Continuing
続けて…
Physical Attack Resistance
acquisition successful.
“物理攻撃耐性”獲得
成功しました
Physical Attack Resistance
Acquisition
Successful.
救急車を！　早く！
We need an ambulance! Quick!
It hurts... The blood...
（三上）
痛い… 血が…
Confirmed.
（大賢者）
確認しました
Pain Nullification
Pain Nullification acquired.
“痛覚無効”獲得
血液が不要な体を作成します
[Acquired]
Pain
Nullification
Creating a body that does not require blood.
Creating a body that
does not require blood
（三上）うっ…
（大賢者）成功しました
Successful.
（三上）うぐっ！
Would you... shut up already, Tamura?
（三上）
さっきから… うるさいぞ 田村
Senpai, hang in there!
先輩！　しっかり！
So cold...
（三上）
寒い…
（大賢者）
“対寒耐性”獲得
Cold Resistance acquisition successful.
成功しました
Heat Resistance
Cold Resistance
Acquisition of Heat Resistance
and Cold Resistance
“対熱耐性”“対寒耐性”を
獲得したことにより
Thermal Fluctuation Resistance
results in acquisition of new skill,
Thermal Fluctuation Resistance.
“熱変動耐性”に
スキルが変化しました
Am I... gonna die?
（三上）
俺… 死ぬのか？
T-Tamura...
（三上）たっ 田村…
Take the hard drive out
of my computer at home...
家のパソコン…
ハードディスクの中身
風呂に沈めて
完全に消去してくれ
put it in the bath... and make
sure it's completely wiped.
Huh?
Deletion of data via electric current
（大賢者）
電流によるデータ消去
has failed due to insufficient information.
情報不足により失敗しました
Consistency not found among theoretical values.
代行措置として“電流耐性”獲得
As an alternate measure,
Employing Alternate Measure
Electric Current Resistance acquired.
Electric Current Resistance
Attached is Paralysis Resistance.
付属して“麻痺(まひ)耐性”獲得
Paralysis Resistance
Acquisition successful.
成功しました
Successful.
Senpai...
先輩…
頼む…
Please...
俺…
All I really wanted to do...
was show off Sawatari to you...
ホントは沢渡のこと
先輩に自慢したくて
チッ　ったく…
Jeez...
Don't worry about that.
気にするな
Mikami-san...
三上さん！
彼女のこと
幸せにしてやれよ
Be sure to make her happy.
パソコン 頼んだぞ
And take care of my computer.
I never thought I'd die a virgin...
（三上）
まさか… 童貞のまま死ぬなんて
If I'm reborn, I'll be a lot more aggressive.
生まれ変わったら
ガンガン攻めよう
食いまくって…
I'll screw every girl I see...
（大賢者）
ユニークスキル“捕食者”を獲得
Unique skill: Predator
acquisition successful.
Unique Skill
Predator
Acquired
成功しました
If a guy who's still a
virgin at 30 is a magician,
（三上）
30歳 童貞で 魔法使いなら
then, given how close I was
to 40, I would've been a sage.
40近い俺は
もうすぐ賢者だったのに
I could've even made it
to the rank of great sage.
大賢者も夢じゃないが…
Extra skill: Sage acquisition successful.
（大賢者）
エクストラスキル“賢者”を獲得
Extra Skill
Sage
Acquired
続けて“賢者”を
Continuing, Sage will transform
into the unique skill Great Sage.
Sage will transform into
the unique skill Great Sage
ユニークスキル“大賢者”に
進化させます
Sage will transform into
the unique skill Great Sage
Unique Skill
Great Sage
Successful.
成功しました
Unique Skill
Great Sage
Successful
Oh, shut up...
（三上）
うるせえな
そろそろ 静かに…
Just let me... have some... quiet time...
してくれよ
先輩…
Senpai...
Senpai!
先輩！
（三上）
何も… 見えない
I can't see anything.
Episode 1: The Storm Dragon, Verudora
ここは どこだ？
Where am I?
ってか どうなった？
And... what happened?
I feel like someone was teasing me
about being a sage, or a great sage...
なんか賢者だ 大賢者だと
バカにされたような…
そうだ 刺されて…
That's right... I was stabbed and...
Okay, I remember. It's all right.
よし 覚えてる 大丈夫だ
まだ慌てる時間じゃない
This isn't the time to panic yet.
The only time I ever lost my cool was
when I crapped my pants in grade school.
クールな俺が慌てたことなんて
小学生のころ ウンコ
漏らしたときぐらいのことだ
Okay, so... I was stabbed, and then...
えっと 刺されて そして…
どこも痛くない
I don't... hurt anywhere.
I'm not cold.
寒くない
My eyes... won't open?
目が… 開かない？
何も見えない
I can't see anything!
My hands... my feet...
手… 足…
ん？　感じない
I can't feel them.
My body...
体は…
おお！　動く
I can move!
So I have sensation.
感覚はある
Are those... rocks?
これは… 岩か？
Rock
てことは 病院ではない？
Which would mean I'm not in the hospital...
Then, where the hell am I?
じゃあ どこだよ
ん？　これは…
Is this...
some kind of plant?
草… かな？
Does my mouth work?
口は動くか？　声は…
My voice...
出ない
Nope.
Huh? It dissolved?
えっ 溶けた？
ああ… 体の中に しみ渡る
Plant
Intake
It's permeating throughout my body...
Disappear
Surge
俺… どうなってるの？
What's happened to me?
Something seems weird.
なんか変じゃね？
Humans can't usually
dissolve plants, can they?
普通 人間って
草 溶かせなくね？
Oh... Huh? Eh?
Maybe I really did die...
やっぱ 死んじゃったのかな
田村と沢渡さん どうなった？
What happened to Tamura and Sawatari-san?
ハードディスクは消去されたのか？
Did he wipe my hard drive?
Just... what the heck am I right now?
俺… 今 一体 どうなってんの？
Hey, I bounce. I seem
to have some elasticity.
（スライム）
弾むな… なにか弾力がある
えっと 体の外側は…
Let's see, my body's exterior is...
Uh-huh.
（スライム）
ほう ほう…
I see, I see.
なるほど なるほど…
How can this be?!
なんということでしょう！
I was such a hot,
manly man (self-proclaimed),
あんなに かっこよくて
男らしかったのに
Manly
かっこ 自称 かっこ閉じ
(Self-proclaimed)
今では こんなに流線的な
洗練されたスタイルに！
but now I've taken on this
refined, streamlined form!
Yeah, right, idiot!
Like hell I can accept that!
って アホか！
認められるか〜！
But... I am a slime, aren't I?
でも… スライムだよな
Yeah. I'm not human.
うん… 人間じゃない
It seems like I got stabbed,
died, and reincarnated...
どうやら 刺されて死んで
転生しちゃったようだ…
as a slime.
スライムに
I think it's been a fairly
long time since then.
（スライム）
それから
結構な日にちが たったと思う
意外なことに この体 結構 便利で
Surprisingly, it turns out
this body is pretty handy.
I don't even need to eat or sleep.
食事も 睡眠も
とらなくて大丈夫のようだ
So why do I eat plants, you ask?
では なぜ 草を食べているかって？
Because I have nothing else to do!
暇 だ･か･ら だよ！
There's no point, but I don't feel
right if I'm not doing something.
意味はないけど
何かしてないと不安だからな
Wait... Who am I even talking to?
って 誰に言ってんだ 俺…
Anyway, I wonder where
this stuff I eat is going.
でも この食べた物
どこへ吸収されているんだろう
I haven't pooped or...
ウンコしてないし
Answer.
（大賢者）解(かい)…
（スライム）うわあ！
It is stored in the stomach
of your unique skill, Predator.
（大賢者）
ユニークスキル“捕食者”の胃袋に
収納されています
Th-That voice... I heard
it when I was stabbed, too!
（スライム）
こ… この声
確か 刺されたときにも聞こえた
Wh-Who are you?
だ… 誰？
（大賢者）
解 ユニークスキル“大賢者”の
効果です
Answer.
It is the effect of your
unique skill, Great Sage.
Unique Skill
Great Sage
In Effect
Now that your ability is established,
能力が定着したため
Ability
Established
you are capable of reacting more quickly.
Reaction Speed
Up
反応を速やかに行うことが
可能となりました
Great Sage...
（スライム）大賢者…
So, um, does "skill" mean my abilities?
ええっと…
スキルって能力のことか？
What is "Predator"?
捕食者って…
（大賢者）
捕食して
対象物を体内に取り込み 解析
It allows you to ingest objects
and analyze them within your body.
Unique Skill
Predator
Mimicry Skill
You can then acquire that object's skills.
その対象物のスキルを習得できます
Absorb Into Body
Analyze
Parallel
Once the analysis is complete, you
can mimic the object, as well.
解析が完了すれば
擬態化も可能です
Oh!
The stomach stores the objects you ingest.
（大賢者）
胃袋は捕食対象を収納し
It can also isolate harmful
objects that cannot be analyzed.
更に 解析の及ばない有害なものを
隔離することも可能
（スライム）
ん〜 す… すごい能力だな
捕食者って
Th-This "Predator" seems like
a pretty amazing ability.
Is it really something a slime should have?
スライムが
持ってていいものなのか？
まあ でも せっかくだから…
But, hey, since I do have it...
じゃあ 試しに
食べた草 解析してくれる？
As a test, can you analyze the plants I ate?
Analysis complete.
（大賢者）
解析が完了しました
Hipokute herbs.
Hipokute Herbs
A valuable herb that only grows
in areas rich in magicules.
in areas rich in magicules,
used in healing potions.
Used as an ingredient in
salves and healing potions.
（スライム）まそ？
Magicules?
Magicules
Magicules.
A special energetic material found in all—
A special energetic material found in all...
（スライム）
んんっ もっと分かりやすく！
Explain it so I can understand!
Magical Beings
Magicules
（大賢者）
魔物にとっては
生命のもとになる物質です
They are the building blocks
of life in all magical beings.
Building blocks of life?
（スライム）生命力…
I get it. This cave must
be full of that stuff,
なるほど
それが この洞窟に満ちて
which is why all these valuable
herbs grow here, right?
貴重な薬草が
たくさん生えてるってことか
で ヒポクテ草とやらの
解析ができて 胃袋で収納
So I can analyze these hipokute herbs
and store them in my stomach.
Does that mean I can create and
store salves and healing potions
つまり 体の中で
傷薬と回復薬を作って
ためておけるってことか？
within my own body?
Affirmative
Precisely.
（大賢者）
そのとおりです
I see!
（スライム）
なるほど！　じゃあ…
Okay, then...
So I gobbled up all the
hipokute herbs in this cave
（スライム）
俺は ここにあるヒポクテ草を
捕食しまくった
and immediately turned them into
potions in my stomach along the way.
それと同時に 胃袋の中では
せっせと薬も作成しておく
Potion
They could come in handy
if I'm ever in trouble...
いざというときに備えて…
というのもあるが
but mostly, I just have nothing else to do.
ほかに やることもないし
（スライム）フウ…
If all those plants are actually some
valuable herb you call hipokute herbs,
その辺の草でさえ
ヒポクテ草とかいう
希少な薬草なんだったら
does that mean this rock
is worth something, too?
この石ころなんかも
価値があったり？
Magistone ore.
（大賢者）
魔鉱石
Magistone
Ore
Minerals that spend long periods
of time in magicule-rich areas
魔素の濃度の高い場所にある
鉱石が
take in magicules until
they become magistone ore.
長い年月をかけて魔素を取り込んで
変異した石
It is very valuable.
とても貴重なものです
Really?! Okay, then!
（スライム）
マジかよ！　じゃあ…
Magistone ore's pretty awesome, too!
魔鉱石もイケてるぜ！
So I gobbled up all the
magistone ore in the cave.
（スライム）
俺は魔鉱石を食いまくった
And there's a ton of it!
いっぱいあるから 食い放題だ〜！
It's an all-you-can-eat buffet!
え… わあっ！
わああ〜！
Um... Did I just... fall in water?
（スライム）
え〜っと…
もしかして 水に落ちた？
湖？
A lake?
スライムって浮かないのか？
So slimes don't float?
今度こそ 死ぬのか？
Am I really gonna die this time?
苦しくないな
I don't feel like I'm suffocating.
Wait, was I even breathing to begin with?
そもそも 俺 呼吸してたっけ？
I guess I wasn't...
してないような…
しかし どうしよう… 困ったな
But what do I do now?
This looks bad.
そうだ！
I know!
I'll just ingest some water and...
水を捕食して…
ぷう〜！
Okay!
オッケー！
Skill: Water Pressure Propulsion acquired.
— Water Pressure Propulsion —
（大賢者）
スキル〝水圧推進〞を
獲得しました
W-Wait... I'm going a little too fast!
あ… あれ？　ちょっと速すぎる？
わ… わあ！
I'm pretty sure I hit that wall,
but I don't feel any pain.
壁にぶつかったような
気がするけど 痛くない
（大賢者）
解 “痛覚無効”を
獲得しているため
Answer.
Pain Nullification
Because you have acquired Pain Nullification,
you will not feel pain.
痛みは発生しません
The physical damage you have taken is 10%.
身体損傷率は１割です
Notice
Physical Damage Taken
10%
Species skill Self-Regeneration
has been activated.
固有スキル“自己再生”が
発動しました
Species Skill
Self-Regeneration
Activated
So I still take damage,
even though I don't feel pain?
（スライム）
痛みはなくとも
ダメージはあるのか
I repaired the part of me that took damage?
ダメージを受けた部分を修復した…
のか？
This body really is convenient!
なんて便利な体なんだろう
But I guess I should be more careful.
しかし
もっと慎重に行動しないとな
（ヴェルドラ）聞こえるか？
（スライム）あっ…
Can you hear me, small one?
（ヴェルドラ）小さき者よ
（スライム）んん？
（ヴェルドラ）
聞こえるか？
小さき者よ
Can you hear me, small one?
Hey! I know you can hear me!
（ヴェルドラ）
おい！　聞こえているだろう？
Y-You're talking to me, aren't you?
（スライム）
お… 俺のことだよな？
Answer me.
（ヴェルドラ）返事をするがよい
Easy for you to say!
（スライム）
って言われても 口がないから
しゃべれないんだよ！
How am I supposed to talk
when I don't have a mouth?!
（ヴェルドラ）おい！
Hey!
Just shut up already, baldy!
（スライム）
もう！　うっさい ハゲ！
Oh? You called me a baldy, eh?
（ヴェルドラ）
ほほう… 我をハゲ呼ばわりするか
I see you have guts.
いい度胸ではないか
Uh...
I was trying to be nice since I
haven't had a visitor in so long,
（ヴェルドラ）
久方ぶりの客人だと思って
下手(したて)に出てやったが…
but you seem to have a death wish.
どうやら死にたいらしいな
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
（スライム）
すみません！　すみません！
思ったことが伝わるとは思わず…
I had no idea you could hear my thoughts!
I don't have a mouth or even eyes, you see...
自分 口もなく 目もない状態でして
（ヴェルドラ）
我の姿を見ての発言かと思ったが
目が見えないのか
It amazed me that you would say
such a thing after seeing me,
but it turns out you can't see me, eh?
All right. I will give you sight.
よし 見えるようにしてやろう
Huh?
（ヴェルドラ）
ただし 条件があるがな
However, there will be conditions.
What do you say?
どうする？
What sort of conditions?
（スライム）どんな条件ですか？
It's simple.
（ヴェルドラ）簡単だ
You must not fear me when you
have the ability to see me,
見えるようになったからといって
我に おびえるな
and you must come talk to me again.
そして また 話をしに来い
That's all.
それだけだ
A good deal for you, is it not?
お前にとっては 良い話だろう？
（スライム）
それだけでいいんですか？
That's all I have to do?
（ヴェルドラ）
うむ 実はな
300年前に ここに封印されてな
Yes. You see, I was sealed
here 300 years ago.
Ever since then, I've had nothing
to do, and it's unbearably boring.
それから 暇で暇で
どうしようもなく
退屈しておったのだ
What do you say?
どうだ？
I'm curious as to why you were sealed, but...
（スライム）
封印ってのが気になりますけど…
Okay, I'll gladly do it!
分かりました　喜んで！
Very well. There is a
skill called Magic Sense.
（ヴェルドラ）よかろう
“魔力感知”というスキルがある
使えるか？
Can you use it?
No, I can't.
（スライム）いや 使えないです
（ヴェルドラ）
周囲の魔素を感知するスキルだ
It allows you to sense
the magicules around you.
If I can detect magicules,
I'll be able to see?
（スライム）
魔素を感知すると
目が見えるようになる？
Okay, I guess I'll try it.
まあ やってみるか
ふん！
Hey, there's something...
おっ なんか…
Is this the stuff you call magicules?
これが魔素ってやつか？
Extra skill: Magic Sense acquired.
（大賢者）
エクストラスキル
“魔力感知”を獲得
Extra Skill
Magic Sense
Acquired
That easily?!
（スライム）
そんな あっさり？
Also, "extra"?
ていうか エクストラ？
Extra?
Skills with power and efficiency magnitudes
higher than those of normal skills.
（大賢者）
通常のスキルよりも
威力 性能が桁違いのスキルです
Magic Sense
Wow! "Extra" sounds awesome!
（スライム）
おお！　いいね エクストラ！
Would you like to use Magic Sense?
Yes!
（スライム）
イエス！
I can see!
見える！　見える！
I can actually see!
見えるぞ〜！
Oh, yeah!
あっ そうだ
I really am a slime.
やっぱ 俺 スライムだ…
Well?
（ヴェルドラ）どうだ？
（スライム）あっ はい
Oh, right!
I did it!
できました！
ありがとうございました
Thanks so much!
D-Dragon?!
ド… ドラゴン！
Allow me to formally introduce myself.
（ヴェルドラ）
では 改めて自己紹介しよう
O-Okay...
（スライム）は… はい
I am the Storm Dragon, Verudora.
（ヴェルドラ）
我が名は 暴風竜ヴェルドラ
Storm Dragon?
（スライム）暴風竜…
（ヴェルドラ）
この世に４体のみ存在する
竜種が一体である
I am one of only four True Dragons
that exist in this world.
Hey, you do remember our promise, don't you?
おい 約束は覚えているな？
O-Of course! I'm not scared at all!
（スライム）
も… もちろんっすよ！
おびえてなどいません
Well, I'll come to chat again sometime!
じゃ また 話しに来ますんで！
Hold it!
（ヴェルドラ）待て！
（スライム）ひいっ…
This is indeed unusual.
（ヴェルドラ）実に珍しい…
Slimes are normally low-ranked
monsters that don't think,
スライムは本来
思考もしない低位モンスター
but you have self-awareness.
それなのに自我がある…
ユニークか？
Are you Unique?
What does "Unique" mean?
（スライム）
ユニークといいますと？
It refers to a being with
extraordinary abilities.
（ヴェルドラ）
異常な能力を持つ個体のことだ
I'm not really sure.
（スライム）
ちょっと よく分からないっす
The thing is, I used to be a human,
その 自分… 人間だったんですけど
but I got stabbed and died, and next
thing I knew, I looked like this.
刺されて死んで 気が付いたら
こんな姿になってて
（ヴェルドラ）なるほど 転生者か
I see. You were reincarnated.
（スライム）
転生… やっぱり
スライムに生まれ変わったんですね
Reincarnated...
So I really was reborn as a slime...
You came into this world
in a very unusual way.
（ヴェルドラ）
お前 ものすごく
まれな生まれ方をしたな
（スライム）え… まれ？
Huh? Unusual?
There are occasionally those who
come here from other worlds,
（ヴェルドラ）
異世界からやって来る者は
たまにいるが
but you are the first I've known
of to be reincarnated here.
転生者は 我の知る限り初めてだ
Most would be unable to withstand having
only their soul traverse worlds.
魂だけで世界を渡ると
普通は耐えられないからな
So you're saying
（スライム）
てことは 転生じゃなくて
there are people who came here from other
worlds, but not through reincarnation?
異世界から こっちに
渡ってきた人はいるんですね？
Indeed. We call them Otherworlders.
（ヴェルドラ）
うむ “異世界人”と呼ばれている
そういう者たちは
I've heard that they gain special abilities
when they cross into this world.
世界を渡る際に
特殊な能力を獲得するらしい
I see... I guess that's
how I got my skills, too.
（スライム）
なるほど… 俺のスキルも それかな
もしかしたら日本人もいるかも…
There might even be other
Japanese people here...
I think I'd like to try and find
some of these Otherworlders.
ちょっと その異世界人を探して
会ってみたいと思います
What? You're leaving already?
（ヴェルドラ）
なんだ… もう行ってしまうのか？
He's pouting!
（スライム）しょんぼりしてる！
えっ え〜と…
もう少し いようかな
U-Um... Maybe I'll stay a little longer.
どうせ暇ですし
It's not like I have anything to do...
（ヴェルドラ）
そうか！　ゆっくりしていくがよい
Oh, good! Stay as long as you like!
So, um, you said earlier that
you were sealed here, right?
え〜っと ヴェルドラさん
さっき 封印されてたって
言ってましたよね？
（ヴェルドラ）
よくぞ聞いてくれた！
I'm glad you asked that!
It was 300 years ago...
300年前のことだ
I sort of turned a town into ashes by mistake.
ちょっと うっかり
街を１つ 灰にしちゃってな
"Sort of"?
（スライム）
“しちゃってな”って…
So someone came looking to slay me.
（ヴェルドラ）
そんな我を討伐に来た者がいた
It's certainly true that I
underestimated my opponent a bit.
ちょびっと相手をナメてたのは
間違いない
I started putting my full strength
into the battle partway through...
それでも
途中から本気を出したのだがな…
But I still lost!
負けてしまったな！
But you seem really strong.
（スライム）
ヴェルドラさん
すごい強そうなのに
Was your opponent that powerful?
相手は
そんなに強かったのですか？
Yes, very powerful.
（ヴェルドラ）ああ 強かったよ
“加護”を受けた人間の
“勇者”と呼ばれる存在だ
It was someone known to the humans as
a hero blessed with divine protection.
（スライム）
人間の勇者…
まるでゲームみたいだな
A human hero? Sounds like
something out of a video game.
（ヴェルドラ）
ユニークスキル
〝絶対切断〞で
She overpowered me with her unique
skill, Absolute Severance,
— Absolute Severance —
我を圧倒！
and then she sealed me using
Unlimited Imprisonment.
そして 〝無限牢獄(ろうごく)〞で
我を封印したのだ
Unlimited Imprisonment
（スライム）
その光ってるのが無限牢獄なのか？
Is that shiny stuff her
Unlimited Imprisonment?
Yes.
（ヴェルドラ）
ああ　その勇者は自分のことを
The hero called herself a "Summon."
“召喚者”だと言っておったな
Summon
A Summon?
（スライム）
召喚者…
異世界人とは違うのですか？
Is that different from Otherworlders?
It takes more than 30 mages to perform
a ritual that lasts several days
（ヴェルドラ）
30人以上の魔法使いで
何日もかけて儀式を行い
to bring one here from another world.
異世界から呼び出すのだ
Oh! So there are mages here!
（スライム）
おお！　魔法使いがいる世界なのか
This sounds more and more like a game!
ますますゲームっぽい
（ヴェルドラ）
強力な“兵器”としての役割も
期待されておる
They're also expected to
serve as powerful weapons.
Weapons?
（スライム）兵器？
Yes, for the Summoner.
（ヴェルドラ）召喚主のな
Magic is used to carve a
curse into the Summon's soul
召喚者は召喚主に逆らえないように
魔法で魂に呪いを刻まれる
to ensure that the Summon
can't defy the Summoner.
What the heck?! That's just cruel!
（スライム）
なんじゃそりゃ！
ひどい話ですね
Cruel, eh?
（ヴェルドラ）ひどいか…
元の世界では
どうだったか知らぬが
I don't know what your world was like,
but survival of the fittest is the
prevailing truth in this world.
この世界では
弱肉強食こそが絶対なる真理だ
I see...
（スライム）
そっか…
So you've been in here ever
since that hero sealed you?
で その勇者に封印されて
それから ずっと ここで？
That's right.
（ヴェルドラ）そういうことだ
もう 暇で暇で…
I'm so very bored...
I felt pretty damn lonely just because
I never had a girlfriend in 37 years...
（スライム）
俺は 37年 恋人がいなかっただけで
結構 寂しかったぞ
I can't imagine being all alone for 300 years.
300年１人きりって どれだけ…
よし！
Okay!
Why don't you and I be friends?
じゃあ 俺と友達にならないか？
（ヴェルドラ）ん？　なんだと！
What?! A mere slime proposes friendship
with me, the feared Storm Dragon?!
スライムの分際で
暴風竜と恐れられる この我と
友達だと？
I-If you don't want to, I understand...
（スライム）
いっ 嫌ならいいんだけど…
F-Fool! No one said I didn't want to!
（ヴェルドラ）
バ… バカ！
誰も嫌だと言っておらぬだろうが
Uh, really? Then... what do you say?
（スライム）
えっ そう？
じゃあ どうする？
Yes, well... if you insist...
（ヴェルドラ）
そうだな どうしてもというなら…
I guess I'm willing to think about it.
考えてやっても… いいんだからね
Are you some tsundere?!
（スライム）
ツンデレか！
Yes, I insist! So that settles it!
うん どうしてもだ　決定な！
If you refuse, we're through.
I'll never come here again!
嫌なら絶交　二度と来ない
W-Well, all right. I'll be your friend.
You'd better be grateful!
（ヴェルドラ）し… しかたないな
お前の友達になってやるわ
感謝せよ！
（スライム）素直じゃないねえ
Just can't be honest, can you?
Well, glad to know ya!
じゃあ よろしく！
I-Indeed.
（スライム）
いい年して 友達って
ちょっと照れるけど…
It's a little embarrassing talking
about "friends" at my age...
（スライム）
こうして俺は
通り魔に刺されて 死んで
But that's the story of
how I got stabbed, died,
reincarnated as a slime,
スライムに転生して
and became friends with
the Storm Dragon Verudora.
暴風竜ヴェルドラと友達になった
My totally normal,
uneventful life... is no more.
なんということもない普通の人生…
では もうない
How could this have happened?
なんということでしょう！
こんな人生が待っているとは
I never dreamed a life like
this was waiting for me!
Or should I call it a "slife"?
いや… スライム生(せい)？
I wonder if Tamura wiped
my hard drive for me...
（スライム）
田村 ハードディスク
消去してくれたかなあ
I hope he didn't look at it first.
あいつ 消す前に
中 見なかっただろうな
* Never attempt this.
先輩 安らかに お眠りください
Rest in peace, Senpai.
子供が産まれて男の子だったら
“悟”って付けます
If I ever have a son, I'll name him Satoru.
Next time, "Meeting the Goblins."
（大賢者）
次回「ゴブリンたちとの出会い」
Meeting the Goblins